<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-05-31T01:47:28.769Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-05-31T01:47:28.769Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.9.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Favicons for WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341163</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/dynamic-favicons-for-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-28T14:36:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Typically, a single favicon is used across a whole domain. But there are times you wanna step it up with different favicons depending on context. A website might change the favicon to match the content being viewed. Or a site …
The post Dynamic Favicons for WordPress appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341298</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/to-or-not-to-displaying-terminal-code-snippets/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T18:22:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s very popular to put a $ on lines that are intended to be a command in code documentation that involves the terminal (i.e. the command line).
Like this:
$ brew install somepackage
The point of that is that it …
The post To $ or Not to $: Displaying Terminal Code Snippets appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Show Images on Click]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341020</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/how-to-show-images-on-click/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:25:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most images on the web are superfluous. If I might be a jerk for a bit, 99% of them aren’t even that helpful at all (although there are rare exceptions). That’s because images don’t often complement the text they’re …
The post How to Show Images on Click appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Rendle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340910</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/rethinking-postgres-in-a-post-server-world/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T14:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Serverless architectures have brought engineering teams a great number of benefits. We get simpler deployments, automatic and infinite scale, better concurrency, and a stateless API surface. It’s hard to imagine going back to the world of managed services, broken local …
The post Rethinking Postgres in a Post-Server World appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Rispoli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build a chat app using gRPC and React]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/build-a-chat-app-using-grpc-and-reactjs</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/build-a-chat-app-using-grpc-and-reactjs"/>
        <updated>2021-05-27T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, we will demonstrate how to use gRPC by building a chat app. We will describe in detail how you can set up a gRPC service and then communicate with it from a React app. The chat messages sending back and forth will be handled by a gRPC service. Let's see how it's done, but first, let's learn what gRPC is.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Standalone (Web Components)]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=339759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/awesome-standalone-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his last An Event Apart talk, Dave made a point that it’s really only just about right now that Web Components are becoming a practical choice for production web development. For example, it has only been about a year …
The post Awesome Standalone (Web Components) appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Web Components]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340901</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-web-components/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T17:56:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How we use Web Components at GitHub — Kristján Oddsson talks about how GitHub is using web components. I remember they were very early adopters, and it says here they released a <relative-time> component in 2014! Now they’ve got a 
…
The post Links on Web Components appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340705</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/a-thorough-analysis-of-css-in-js/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T14:08:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wondering what’s even more challenging than choosing a JavaScript framework? You guessed it: choosing a CSS-in-JS solution. Why? Because there are more than 50 libraries out there, each of them offering a unique set of features.
We tested 10 different …
The post A Thorough Analysis of CSS-in-JS appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notion API, Ethereum Development, WWDC21 - Picks #181]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/notion-api-ethereum-development-wwdc21-picks-181</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/notion-api-ethereum-development-wwdc21-picks-181"/>
        <updated>2021-05-26T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Notion API is out, learn Ethereum development, RSVP to WWDC 21 and more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340759</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/what-i-learned-building-a-word-game-app-with-nuxt-on-google-play/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T14:25:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I fell in love with coding the moment I created my first CSS :hover effect. Years later, that initial bite into interactivity on the web led me to a new goal: making a game.
Table of contents
What’s the game 
…
The post What I Learned Building a Word Game App With Nuxt on Google Play appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Collinsworth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fastify authentication strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/fastify-authentication-strategy</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/fastify-authentication-strategy"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Authenticating users to our application prevents the wrong people from gaining access to our service. Without strong authentication and proper implementation strategies, our service could be compromised. In this article, we would look at how to implement a custom authentication strategy in Fastify.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341383</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/creating-powerful-websites-with-serverless-driven-cms-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-25T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choosing the right tools to build a website for your organization is essential, but it can be tough to find the right fit. Simple site builders like Wix and Squarespace are easy for marketers to use, but severely limit developers …
The post Creating Powerful Websites with Serverless-Driven CMS Development appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ahmed Bouchefra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Links on Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340808</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/links-on-performance/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T22:03:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making GitHub’s new homepage fast and performant — Tobias Ahlin describes how the scrolling effects are done more performantly thanks to IntersectionObserver and the fact that it avoids the use of methods that trigger reflows, like getBoundingClientRect. Also, 
…
The post Links on Performance appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[proxy-www]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=341153</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/justjavac/proxy-www"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T19:09:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I like a good trick. What if… a URL was…  a promise… that fetched said URL?
www.codepen.io.then((response) ={
  console.log(response);
});
That’s what @justjavac did with JavaScript Proxys. A clever trick, that. Don’t @ me about the practicality. Trick…
The post proxy-www appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340626</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/wrangling-control-over-pdfs-with-the-adobe-pdf-embed-api/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T13:57:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By our last estimate, there are now more PDFs in the world than atoms in the universe (not verified by outside sources) so chances are, from time to time, you’re going to run into a PDF document or two. Browsers …
The post Wrangling Control Over PDFs with the Adobe PDF Embed API appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raymond Camden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[gRPC vs. REST: pros and cons and technical comparison]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/grpc-vs-rest</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/grpc-vs-rest"/>
        <updated>2021-05-24T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[So is gRPC better than REST? No, I think you choose the one that your use-case demands. Learn when it's best to use REST and when you should choose gRPC.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade?]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340991</id>
        <link href="https://www.stefanjudis.com/blog/should-devtools-teach-the-css-cascade/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T23:22:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Judis, two days before I mouthed off about using (X, X, X, X) for talking about specificity, has a great blog post not only using that format, but advocating that browser DevTools should show us that value by …
The post Should DevTools teach the CSS cascade? appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My takeaways from Google I/O Event 2021 as a developer]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/my-takeaways-from-google-i-o-event-2021</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/my-takeaways-from-google-i-o-event-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The annual Google IO developer conference kicked off with a two-hour keynote filled with announcements. Here are the highlights.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Svelte for the Experienced React Dev]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340825</id>
        <link href="https://css-tricks.com/svelte-for-the-experienced-react-dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:30:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post is an accelerated introduction to Svelte from the point of view of someone with solid experience with React. I’ll provide a quick introduction, and then shift focus to things like state management and DOM interoperability, among other things. …
The post Svelte for the Experienced React Dev appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Rackis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Hell]]></title>
        <id>https://css-tricks.com/?p=340919</id>
        <link href="https://csshell.dev/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-21T14:29:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collection of common CSS mistakes, and how to fix them
From Stefánia Péter. 
Clever idea for a site! Some of them are little mind-twisters that could bite you, and some of them are honing in on best practices that …
The post CSS Hell appeared first on CSS-Tricks.
You can support CSS-Tricks by being an MVP Supporter.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Coyier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[gRPC: detailed guide to the core concepts]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/introduction-to-grpc</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/introduction-to-grpc"/>
        <updated>2021-05-20T14:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[gRPC is a robust open-source high-performance RPC framework released by Google in 2015. It is a standardized, general-purpose, and cross-platform RPC infrastructure that provides scalability, performance, and functionality to distributed applications.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next-Gen CSS, OSS needs you, testing best practices - Picks #180]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/next-gen-css-oss-needs-you-testing-best-practices-picks-180</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/next-gen-css-oss-needs-you-testing-best-practices-picks-180"/>
        <updated>2021-05-19T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about the new CSS container queries, JavaScript testing practices, what you can do for the open-source community, and more!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building modern APIs with Fastify, Graphql, and MongoDB]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/building-modern-apis-with-fastify-graphql-and-mongodb</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/building-modern-apis-with-fastify-graphql-and-mongodb"/>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Both Fastify and GraphQL are great technologies that offer improved speed, flexibility, and easy code maintainability.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GraphQL Subscriptions Work: Tips, Best Practices and Examples.]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/subscriptions-in-graphql</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/subscriptions-in-graphql"/>
        <updated>2021-05-17T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subscriptions is one of the powerful features of GraphQL. In this guide, I cover all you need to know to start with subscriptions in GraphQL.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tailwind CSS from Zero to Hero - The Utility-First Workflow]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/tailwind-css-the-utility-first-workflow</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/tailwind-css-the-utility-first-workflow"/>
        <updated>2021-05-14T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, you got to know more about the core concept behind what makes Tailwind CSS a different CSS framework, i.e. the utility classes. You saw how they are formatted, how they work, how they convert to the usual CSS properties.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building an image gallery with Fastify and React]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/building-an-image-gallery-with-fastify-and-react</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/building-an-image-gallery-with-fastify-and-react"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T12:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we would see how Fastify handles file upload as we build an image gallery using Fastify and React. We would work with Cloudinary and Fastify-multer a Fastify alternative to the express middleware multer.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Git Bisect for Debugging]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/how-to-use-git-bisect-for-debugging</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/how-to-use-git-bisect-for-debugging"/>
        <updated>2021-05-13T07:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s think about when bisect can be useful. Then we’ll go through a tutorial. Lastly, I’ll cover some advanced features and go over some caveats.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Money with Code, Bootstrap 5, Is Docker Dead - Picks #179]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/making-money-with-code-bootstrap-5-is-docker-dead-picks-179</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/making-money-with-code-bootstrap-5-is-docker-dead-picks-179"/>
        <updated>2021-05-12T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to make money with code, is Docker dead, and finally, Bootstrap 5 is here! All this and more on this week's picks! Check them out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything you need to know about GraphQL Authentication and Authorization]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/authentication-and-authorization-in-graphql</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/authentication-and-authorization-in-graphql"/>
        <updated>2021-05-06T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn about authentication and how it can be implemented in a GraphQL API using Express.js and APolloServer.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding Practices, MERN Stack, Working With TypeScript - Picks 178]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/coding-practices-mern-stack-working-with-typescript-picks-178</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/coding-practices-mern-stack-working-with-typescript-picks-178"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how to clean your code, build an app using the MERN stack, and more on our new weekly picks edition]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to build blazing fast APIs with Fastify and TypeScript]]></title>
        <id>https://daily.dev/blog/how-to-build-blazing-fast-apis-with-fastify-and-typescript</id>
        <link href="https://daily.dev/blog/how-to-build-blazing-fast-apis-with-fastify-and-typescript"/>
        <updated>2021-05-05T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fastify is a must use for all Node.js developers and I hope you give it a try in your next app.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>daily.dev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>